Daniel, Cletus, Papers /4288
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Cletus Daniel Papers
1937-1991
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Daniel, Cletus
/4288
5 cubic feet
5 linear ft.
Papers.
This is a collection of research material that Professor Daniel collected during his tenure at the New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations, Cornell University.
7000804
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, December 19, 2013
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, March 04, 2019
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: /4073: James O. Morris Office Files /4290m: ILR School Dean's Office Memorial Statements /4297: ILR School Biography Files 5584: National Archives and Records Service Copies of Federal Documentation on Black Workers 5584 A: National Archives and Records Service Copies of Federal Documentation on Black Workers 5619/008: ACWA Rieve-Pollock Foundation Files 5981 P: ACTWU Labor Unity Photograph Files
Scope and Contents
Titles with "RG" followed by alphanumeric codes indicate copies of material from the National Archives, with number codes indicating the record group to which each folder belongs.
Collective bargaining; Labor laws and legislation; Labor--History; Daniel, Cletus E., 1943-
7000804
- The ACLU. and the Wagner Act: An Inquiry Into the Depression-Era Crisis of American Liberalism, Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Draft by Daniel. Includes copy of 1957 address by George W. Brooks, Director of Research and Education, International Brotherhood of Pulp Sulphite, and Paper Workers, "What Will Collective Bargaining Look Like in Twenty Years?"
- Chapter X Factories in the Field- Donald Von Eschon, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Origins of Powerlessness: California Farmworkers in the Age of Organization and Reform- Chapter I-IV (Folder 1 of 2), 1978 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Origins of Powerlessness: California Farmworkers in the Age of Organization and Reform- Chapter I-IV (Folder 2 of 2), 1978 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- The Politics of Inequality: The President's Committee on Fair Employment Practice and Chicago Workers during World War II, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- The Politics of Inequality: The President's Committee on Fair Employment Practice and Chicago Workers during World War II, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Research Notes, Undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Daniel Course Evaluations (Box 1, Folder 8)
- In Defense of the Wheatland Wobblies: A Critical Analysis of the I.W.W. in California (Box 1, Folder 9)
- ILR 689, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- ACLU Proposal Amendments to Agricultural Adjustment Act (AAA) and National Labor Relations Act (NLRA), 1935 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Wagner Bill, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Sacramento Criminal Syndicalism Cases, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- ACLU & Wagner Act Debate, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Farm Workers Collective Bargaining Rights Agitation 1935 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Notes, Documents Relating to Labor, Undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Contains background resarch on agricultural labor in the 1930s as well as correspondence of JR Steelman.
- Papers Relating to Labor and Unions in the 1930s, 1934-1939 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Includes US Department of Labor correspondence about agricultural labor disputes in California and other western states. Also includes typewritten notes on the 12th Communist District Secretariat and a memo on the Pacific Coast Secretariat, which "following out the Communist Party plans for more intensive activity on the Pacific Coast [...] will have jurisdiction over all Communistic activity along the coastal states as well as Nevada, Arizona, Utah, and Idaho."
- San Jose Cannery Strike, 1931 RG 13 170-6504 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- El Monte Strike, 1933 RG 13 170-8083 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  Contains material relating to Mexican farm laborers striking for higher wages against Japanese berry growers.
- In Defense of the Wheatland Wobblies: A Critical Analysis of the I.W.W. in California & Articles from The New Republic, 1933-1934 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- American Marquis and American Magazine articles, 1934-1958 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- 1934 New Republic and American Federationist photocopies, Undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
- 1933 ACLU Vol. 6/13 photocopies, Undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
- 1933 IJA Monthly Bulletins Reel 5 photocopies, Undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
- 1935 ACLU Vol. 772 photocopies, Undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
- 1934 ACLU Vol. 719 photocopies, Undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
- 1934 ACLU Vol. 718 photocopies, Undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
- 1934 ACLU Vol. 705 photocopies, Undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
- 1934 ACLU Vol. 775 photocopies, Undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
- 1934 ACLU Vol. 706 photocopies, Undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
- 1933 ACLU Vol. 598 photocopies, Undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
- 1933 ALCU Vol. 607 photocopies, Undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
- 1931 ACLU Record Reels 3 and 4 photocopies, Undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
- 1934 ACLU Vol. 721 photocopies, Undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
- 1933 ACLU Record Reel 4 Minutes photocopies, Undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
- 1954 ACLU Vol 698 photocopies, Undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
- 1933 ACLU Record Reel 4 Press Releases photocopies, Undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
- 1933 ACLU Records Reel 5 Press Bulletins photocopies, Undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
- 1933 ACLU Vol. 618 photocopies, Undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
- 1934 ACLU Vol. 696 photocopies, Undated (Box 2, Folder 25)
- 1935 ACLU Vol 777 photocopies, Undated (Box 2, Folder 26)
- 1937 IJA Bulletins photocopies, Undated (Box 2, Folder 27)
- 1934 ACLU Records Reel 5 Press Bulletins photocopies, Undated (Box 2, Folder 28)
- 1934 The Communist photocopies, Undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
- 1933 The Communist photocopies, Undated (Box 2, Folder 30)
- 1934 IJA Monthly Bulletins 1934 Reel 5 photocopies, Undated (Box 2, Folder 31)
- 1934 ACLU Records Reel 5 Minutes photocopies, Undated (Box 2, Folder 32)
- 1955 ACLU Vol. 780 photocopies, Undated (Box 2, Folder 33)
- 1937-1940 ACLU Records Reel 31 Policy Guides photocopies, Undated (Box 2, Folder 34)
- 1935 ACLU Vol. 784 photocopies, Undated (Box 2, Folder 35)
- 1880-1904 Transactions of the California State Agriculture Society and Other Documents photocopies, Undated (Box 2, Folder 36)
- 1880-1905 Transactions of the California State Agricultural Society photocopies, Undated (Box 2, Folder 37)
- 1938 Transactions of the California State Agricultural Society and Other Documents Relating to Labor in the USA photocopies, Undated (Box 2, Folder 38)
- 1937 United Cannery, Agricultural, Packing, and Allied Workers of America photocopies, Undated (Box 2, Folder 39)
- 1938-1940 Milwaukee County Industrial Union Council photocopies, Undated (Box 2, Folder 40)
- RG 13 /99-1189 Pecan Shellers Strike, 1938 U.S. Amer. Service, 1933-1936 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Saturday Review and Archives Research Item List, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Federal Emergency Relief Act (FERA) in California 1933-1934, Undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Filipino Vegetarian Workers' Strike, 1931 U.S. Commissioner of Conciliation RG 13 170-6125, Undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Fruit and Vegetable Packers Strike, 1932 RG 13 170-725 US Commissioner of Conciliation Service, Undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  Material documents lead up to a strike motivated by Fruit and Vegetable Packers Association's demand for Immigration Services to investigate Japanese workers.
- Proceedings of Meeting No.1 of the Special Industrial Recovery Board and Letters to Government Officials, 1930-1971 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  Contains material related to the National Recovery Act. Also includes some material on Mexican agricultural workers.
- Seabrook Farms Strike, 1934 RG 13 170-9817 U.S. Commissioner of Conciliation Service, Undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Legal Cases Relating to Agricultural Workers, Ironworkers, Bricklayers, Carpenters in California, Undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Papers and Newspapers Relating to the IWW, 1913-1917 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  Includes Bureau of Industrial Research pamphlet titled "Agriculture: The World's Basic Industry and Its Workers," "Twenty Fiver Years of Industrial Unionism" IWW pamphlet, various documents and newspaper clippings.
- Material Relating to the IWW and Labor Articles Relating to Agriculture, 1913-1917 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Howell "The IWW and the Espionage Act" (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Notes and Papers Relating to Labor+ Agriculture in California, 1915-1921 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- List of References on Migrants and Related Subjects in the SRA Library, 1930 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Social Science Research Council Bibliography of P.C. Agri Labor (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Papers Relating to Agriculture and Labor, 1934-1937 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Agricultural Workers and the AAA, 1935 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Farm Workers Support, 1931-38, 1937-1938 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Philip Bancroft Interviews (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Wofford B, Camp Interviews, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Papers Relating to the Wagner Act + Labor Journals, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Imperial Valley Strikes, 1930 U.S. Com. Service RG 13 170-5463, 1939-1944 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Origins of Powerlessness: California Farmworkers in the Age of Organization and Reform- Preface+ Chapter 1-4 (Folder 1 of 2) (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Origins of Powerlessness: California Farmworkers in the Age of Organization and Reform- Chapter 4-8 (Folder 2 of 2) (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Newspapers, 1934 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Speeches, etc. Supporting Agricultural Unionism, 1934 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Reports, etc. on Imperial Valley, 1934 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Oxnand Beet Workers' Strike, 1933 U.S. Com. Service RG 13 170-9201 176-413 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Communist Party Materials, 1927-1930 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Fresno Bee+ s-f Examine + Letter, 1933 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- ACLU and 1933 Cotton Strikes (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Anti-Filipino Activities in Salinas Valley, 1934 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- ACLU Correspondence with Gen. Glassford WPA/FNP, 1934 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Internal ACLU Correspondence Re Imperial Valley, 1934 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Miscellaneous Materials re Imperial Valley, 1933 Strikes, Growers Activities, etc., 1934-1937 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Miscellaneous Correspondences in Imperial Valley, 1934 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Imperial Valley, 1934 RG 13 170-7205 U.S. Com. Service (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Orange Pickers' Strike, 1936 U.S. Com Service RG 13 182-1525 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Creed Correspondence, other materials re 1933 Cotton Strike and Aftermath, 1933-1935 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Cotton Strike, 1933 U.S. Com. Service RG 13 176-635, 1933-1935 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Mexican Labor Union, 1934 RG 13 170-7205 U.S. Com. Service (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Agricultural Labor Relations in General, mid 1934 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Salinas Strikes, 1928-1935 U.S. Com. Service RG 13 176-654 182-931 170-4693 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Cotton Pickers, San Joaquin Valley, 1935-37 U.S. Com. Service RG 13 182-763 (Box 4, Folder 20)
- American Federation of Labor, Report of Proceedings, 1934-1935 (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Materials re NLB Activism in Salinas Valley, 1934, 1934-1935 (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Agricultural Labor Disputes, Salhen California, 1935 U.S. Com. Service RG 13 182-77, 1934-1935 (Box 4, Folder 23)
- ACLU Efforts to get Federal Achieve in Imperial Valley, 1934, 1934-1935 (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Materials From Justice Dept. Re Federal Interpretation in Imperial Valley, 1934 (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Articles Relating to Agriculture and Labor, 1937-1939 (Box 4, Folder 26)
- Speeches, etc. Against Agricultural Unionism, 1934 (Box 4, Folder 27)
- San Maria Valley, 1934 (Box 4, Folder 28)
- Anti-Farm Labor Activities of State Government., June, 1934 (Box 4, Folder 29)
- C.A.W.I.U. Materials, 1933 (Box 4, Folder 30)
- Fed. Govt. and Calif. Red Scare, 1934 (Box 4, Folder 31)
- Sacramento C.S. Cases, 1934 (Box 4, Folder 32)
- Internal ACLU Correspondence on Imperial Valley, 1934 (Box 4, Folder 33)
- Materials re States of Farm Labor Under NIRA Sec.7 (a), 1933-1934 (Box 4, Folder 34)
- Los Angles Regional Labor Board Materials in Imperial Valley, 1934 RG 25, NLB,IX,NA (Box 4, Folder 35)
- US Department of Labor Reports + Articles Relating to Labor, 1934-1935 (Box 4, Folder 36)
- Salinas Lettuce Packers' Strike- 1936 U.S. Conciliation Service File No. 182-1416 Record Group 13, 1939 (Box 4, Folder 37)
- In Defense of the Wheatland Wobblies (Box 4, Folder 38)
- Yakima Valley Strikes- 1933 (Box 4, Folder 39)
- Newbill Article on Yakima Strike, 1910-1936 (Box 4, Folder 40)
- Articles Relating to Labor, 1913-1914 (Box 4, Folder 41)
- Writings by Prof. Cletus Daniel + Agricultural Economic Bibliographies (Folder 1 of 4), 1975-1978 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Agricultural Economic Bibliographies (Folder 2 of 3), 1975-1978 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Agricultural Economic Bibliographies (Folder 3 of 3), 1975-1978 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Yakima and the Wobblies, 1910-1936 By James G. Newbill (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Professor Evaluations for Prof. Cletus Daniel, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Cornell Inventory for Student Appraisal of Teaching and Courses, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Professor Evaluations for Prof. Cletus Daniel (Box 5, Folder 7)
- The Politics of Inequality: The President's Committee on Fair Employment Practice and Chicano Workers During World War II, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Pacific Northwest Quarterly, and Minutes of the Regular Meetings on the Los Angeles Industrial Union Council, CIO, 1937-1940 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Minutes of the Regular Meeting of the Los Angeles, Industrial Union Council, CIO, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Reference Lists (Folder 1 of 4), 1969 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Reference Lists (Folder 2 of 4), 1969 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Reference Lists- Agriculture (Folder 3 of 4), 1941-1942 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Reference Lists- Agriculture (Folder 4 of 4), 1953 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- An Injury to One is an Injury to Some: Inter-Union Relations in the U.S. Airline Industry, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 15)